Imayan Gowthaman

Software Development Specialist

Summary

A passionate full spectrum Software developer/Integrator with years of experience in designing, developing and deploying software solutions for Manufacturing, Insurance & SaaS companies. I'm an advocate for functional, Integration, Reporting and user-centered products which has an impact on people's life solving a need. I have a strong notion that a good product is a concoction of design and technology.

Education

Master of Science, Computer Science DePaul

University, Chicago - Jun 2021 (Expected)

Professional Experience

Senior Software Engineer, Accenture

Jun 2018 - Jan 2019

Developed a Web Portal which allows customer to interact with business users of Canadian mortgage Housing Corp using Knockout JS, Restful API and Angular. Creation of Automation Test cases for unit testing using fakes CRM framework. Involved in Development of an automation system to migrate millions of data from legacy systems to current systems using Sequel Server integration services.

Senior Developer, HCL Corporation

April 2016- May 2018

Developed an Automated verification system for Insurance companies by interpreting the source info with data retrieved from verified external systems using c#. Also Created a Custom web based Angular form which retrieves and compares the info on-demand. Verification system is capable of handling Source data in XML, JSON, Ascii file format.

Software Engineer, Tech Mahindra

August 2013 – April 2016

Involved in Development of a Price Calculation Engine for renew and repair products in OTIS using Restful API, JavaScript, XRM Framework and c# .

Involved in development and integration of an HTML 5 Application to geolocate the nearby OTIS support premises within the specified range.

Involved in Custom Report Generation for Forecasting and displaying sale charts. Involved in Design and Integration of MSCRM Mobile App with desktop Application.

App Developer, DePaul University

Feb 2019-Present

Involved in planning, designing and development of Student interaction App in both IOS and Android using google API, objective c and java.

+1 312-785-0828 gowtham.ongc@gmail.com

Key Skills

MSCRM Specialist

C++ Optimization

SSIS Integrator

Reporting

UI Designer

Testing Automation Usability

Testing

Web Development using angular/Angular CLI

Object Oriented Development

Software Dev Life Cycle

Scaled Agile

Tools

IntelliJ, Visual Studio, SSRS, SSIS, Azure.

Databases

SQL Server 2005/2008, Oracle SQL Developer

Development

C++,C#,Java,Angular,SQL,Python,R,
HTML, CSS, Javascript , jQuery,
ReactJS,AWS S3. Spring Boot • Jira
• Confluence • Jenkins • Bamboo •
Bitbucket • XCode • Google Cloud
• Git • Android Studio •
IntelliJ/PyCharm • Python IDLE •
Jupyter Notebook • Adobe
Photoshop • Illustrator • Final Cut
Pro • Word Press • Express Engine

Activities

Developer Student Club-Google

College Projects

Optimizing Particle Engine using C++